[MUSIC]
Hello and welcome.
I'm Andrei Panko, and I
will be doing demos for you.
Demos of demo data, sounds interesting.
So, you know that
we are slightly moving from
configuration packages
into Contoso Coffee demo data tool,
which contains different scenarios.
And in this season,
we change how tool looks, and
we also added support of
missing service management model.
Now it includes the data to
demonstrate two very different scenarios.
And I will do a
quick demo for you in a moment.
Let's start by taking a
quick look at the Contoso demo tool.
I will search for Contoso, and now
it is only one page related to this one.
So we removed the duplicated
pages, because now all models are listed here.
And you can see
the service model is added.
You can open the configuration
pages, which are now dramatically simpler.
And because we moved shared
details into the common model, all right?
So for example, sales tax, the
company type, which decides on a tax calculation,
or currency details are listed here.
You don't need to
define them in each one.
And because this model is
dependent, you just run one functional model.
And you can run it
in two different modes.
You can run it in the generate
means full and setup and demo data,
means master data
and transactions included.
Or generate setup data only, means
you can get number series and various setups
in the company, but not master data.
Then you can load your data
somehow else, somehow differently.
I don't need to run anything, because
it's already executed in the pre-installed
packages, pre-installed companies.
But if you create a new
company, you might want to try it.
And now we have enough demo data to
demonstrate two very different scenarios,
both in the service area.
I will start with ad hoc service order.
So somebody unknown,
or maybe known, in this case,
it will be our favorite
customer, 10,000, approach our company,
because they have
issues with one of our items.
But it was not us who sold it to them.
So it was somebody else.
That's why we don't
have it as service item created,
but we can actually use a normal item.
And here we can use standard
fancy functionality of the service model.
We can do quick troubleshooting.
Have you tried to
turn it off and on again?
The classical one.
Or you can do more
advanced fault resolution code search.
So what is complaint about?
What is a symptom?
A symptom people complain about noise.
Mm-hmm.
Noise where?
During doing.
All right.
Then probably we need to fix
it in this way, how it is described.
All right. Let's close it.
So now we have a recommendation.
Let's scroll to the right and ask people,
do you need a spare
coffee machine meanwhile?
We are doing repair.
Yes, of course.
We cannot live without coffee.
So let's take something instead.
We are registering replacement.
And probably we need to charge
people a little bit for this replacement.
That's why we use
functions, get standard service code,
and I have one defined
to charge for loaner per day.
All right.
We will fix very fast.
Good.
This one is ready.
So I create a service order.
Now service
technician should be able to take it.
All right.
I am now service technician.
I can see that I have
service order scheduled for today,
and I will just go to
list of the tasks, service tasks.
Usually I have more,
but today I have only one,
and I will start work on it immediately.
I open item worksheet.
I see some details about what I'm fixing,
what are the symptoms and
what are the recommended resolution,
and I will just do my work.
I will register my work as service hours.
So I spend a couple
of hours fixing the stuff.
All right.
Am I done?
Probably yes.
Then I can change status
of the specific line to finished.
Good.
This also, because it's
only one item in the service order,
updates status of
the service order in general.
Good.
Now, back from service
technician to more responsible people,
service managers or person
who is responsible for invoicing,
they see the finished
service order, what they can just do,
go and post it.
Post, ship, and invoice.
Done.
That was very quick
demo of the ad hoc repairs,
and we have some demo
data to support this scenario.
All right.
More advanced scenario, and it
will be involving service contract,
but to do service
contract, we need to have a service item.
We will create service item
automatically when we post sales order.
So let's find the sales order
already created in the system with some item,
and let's ship it
and maybe invoice it as well.
We don't want to look at invoice,
but we want to look at the service contract.
So let's go to the
service contract and create a new one.
Okay.
And we have also
templates, some templates,
examples to
demonstrate different patterns.
We are going to use the
prepayment contract with monthly repair orders.
All right.
Which customer?
The same, the favorite one.
When we will be creating service orders,
because we
actually want not only to charge
for regularly, but we also
want to perform some type of service.
We can also use service
order types to define the difference.
That will be
maintenance type of contract.
It will be easy for us to monitor them.
All right.
Now it's time to add
the lines in the contract.
It will be service item.
It was created
automatically during the posting of shipment.
All right.
Let's add it.
Let's define some
value and sign the contract.
Yes, I want to sign my contract.
And because I'm charging monthly, I
probably need to
charge the remainder of the month.
Yep.
Service contract was created.
Or service invoice, sorry.
I can see it here.
So some statistics, open service invoice.
Take a look at the details.
I can see some gel amounts,
some amounts, and we just go and post it.
All right.
So invoicing is done.
Customer is paying on time.
All good.
Probably we need to
do the actual maintenance.
Let's close the service invoice,
service contract, and sometime passed.
Now we need to do service order.
We will run create
service orders from the
contract task,
which are valid in this month,
which apparently is April.
I will click OK.
Usually it should be more than one order
because probably we
have multiple contracts.
But for demonstration
purpose, one order is always good.
And here it is.
Then from here, we
can do the standard work.
Let's register some resource utilization.
First of all, I want to
assign this order to someone.
I will open the
administration, dispatch board,
and then I have maybe
multiple, maybe one order.
And it's time to do
the resource allocation.
Let's do resource allocation.
Who should work on it?
Resource, when?
Today is a good day.
How long?
Two hours.
I like to work for two hours.
All right.
That's one allocated.
I can use zones or I can use skills to
filter out resource
and assign the proper ones.
Now I will do technician
work the same way as we did before.
We open service task.
We find the stuff to do.
And now I will be using,
again, the same item, work with.
But in this type, I will be using hours.
I'm registering
hours that I'm, as a resource,
spend, okay, not two,
but three hours in reality.
That was a bit longer than expected.
And let's mark it as finished as well.
Okay.
Done, done.
This order is slightly different.
That's why when I, before
posting of it, I will explore.
I will navigate to lines.
I will open order
service lines and change quantity
from quantity to invoice
to zero to quantity to consume.
Because it will be internal consumption.
Because we charge customer
separately via invoicing process.
So these are two parallel
but not very related processes.
Let's post, ship, and consume.
So internal consumption is registered.
All right.
That was a very quick demos of
demo tool, which now has more models.
And you can see we are
moving more and more stuff there.
So sooner or later,
like everything will be there.
Not only for SaaS,
but for on-prem as well.
And this model is very extensible.
So you can just go and add your vertical
functionality if
needed and reuse existing ones.
There is a special
session about it also available.
And that's it.
Let me just give a
standard advertisement of the valuable
resources you have access
to and way to communicate with us.
You can submit ideas about missing
functionality, what we
must add and what is a priority.
This is very helpful.
If you are a partner,
you can join the Yammer group
and participate in the
design discussion in more details.
And get access to preview bits and
provide feedback early feedback sooner.
Thank you very much.
And let's stay in touch.